Before I became Conan Edogawa,
Sebelum aku menjadi Conan Edogawa,
I was brought to Beika Aquarium by Ran
Ran membawaku ke Beika Akuarium
in order to carry out a project entitled
untuk membantu dia menjalankan
"The great coincidental two lovers meet again
"Rencana reuni yang disengaja dan romantis
at the aquarium lovey-dovey project",
di akuarium super",
in an attempt to bring an end to the separation of her parents.
untuk menghentikan perpisahan orang tuanya.
But, there...
Tapi, selagi kami di sana...
The hidden lines on the palm are the fuse.
Garis telapak tangan yang tersembunyi adalah sekeringnya.
The deduction catches fire on the line to the heart.
Garis hati menyalakan api deduksi.
Cell phone movies at the underwater spiral corridor.
Film-film ponsel dalam jalur bawah air.
A queer subject relays the truth.
Sebuah subjek aneh mengungkap kebenaran.
He sees through the one and only truth.
Dia melihat satu-satunya kebenaran.
A child in appearance with the I.Q. of an adult.
Memiliki penampilan seorang anak kecil dengan kepintaran orang dewasa.
His name is Detective Conan!
Namanya adalah Detektif Conan!
"Shinichi Kudo Aquarium Incident (Part 2)"
"Kasus Akuarium Shinichi Kudo (Bagian 2)"
"Beika Aquarium"
"Akuarium Beika"
"Beika Aquarium" -I panicked!
"Akuarium Beika" -Aku takut.
"Kanoko Nakagiri (27), Customer" -I was picked up by him
"Kanoko Nakagiri (27), Tamu Akuarium" -Aku bertemu dia
"Kanoko Nakagiri (27), Customer" -only last week.
"Kanoko Nakagiri (27), Tamu Akuarium" -ketika dia mendekatiku minggu lalu.
I smelled something fishy.
Dia tampak sedikit berbahaya.
I thought it best not to get involved.
Aku mendapat firasat aku harus menjauh darinya.
Wearing a mini skirt, smelling of perfume
Dia mengenakan rok mini, wangi parfum,
and about 5'4".
dan tingginya sekitar 5'4".
See?
Benar?
Then, you're the one who came to this aquarium with the victim?
Jadi, kau yang datang ke akuarium dengan korban?
Yes.
Ya.
When I told him I liked dolphins
Aku bilang aku suka lumba-lumba,
he invited me to come to this aquarium with him.
jadi dia mengundangku ke akuarium.
Then, you saw the dolphin show too, didn't you?
Jadi, kau menonton pertunjukkan lumba-lumba?
Yes! Together with him.
Ya, dengan dia.
But, after he left for the restroom,
Tapi dia pergi ke kamar kecil selama pertunjukkan
he didn't come back.
dan tidak pernah kembali.
The dolphin show finished.
Dia melewatkan pertunjukkan lumba-lumba itu.
So I went looking around for him thinking to give it to him,
Aku mencarinya untuk memarahinya,
but was I shocked out of my wits!
tapi itu mengejutkan!
Because he was collapsed on the floor bleeding.
Dia berada di lantai dan berdarah.
What shocked me even more was after that...
Aku bahkan lebih terkejut lagi kemudian...
The call that came in on his cell phone.
Ketika aku menerima panggilan dari ponselnya.
The people around him seem to have been making a fuss
Semua orang di sekitarku ribut
saying that there was a stabbing incident
mengatakan dia telah ditikam,
so I decided to ignore it.
jadi aku mengabaikannya.
I thought that maybe the one who called
Aku pikir pria menelepon aku
was the one who stabbed him and was coming after me too.
yang menikamnya dan mungkin akan mengincarku.
Why did you think they'd come after you?
Kenapa kau berpikir begitu?
Because he was talking sneakily on his cell phone
Dia sedang melakukan percakapan aneh di ponselnya
about things that sounded dangerous.
mengenai sesuatu yang sepertinya berbahaya.
Like, I'll get the dough ready for sure or whatever.
Sesuatu tentang, "Aku pasti akan mendapatkan uang itu."
Could it be that you're suspecting me if so, you're wrong.
Jika kau pikir aku melakukannya, kau salah.
I have movie to prove it too, you know!
Aku punya bukti video!
The one that I took at the dolphin show a while ago.
Aku mengambil ini selama pertunjukkan lumba-lumba.
The viewers in front are drenched!
Barisan depan basah!
This is funny.
Lucu.
The show ended at 12 pm sharp!
Acara itu berakhir pada siang hari!
-His corpse was found before 12, right? -Yes.
-Kau menemukan jasadnya sebelum itu, bukan? -Ya.
I was recording the dolphin show to the end
Aku merekam seluruh pertunjukkan lumba-lumba itu
and the voice that's recorded is mine too!
malah suaraku ada di dalam video!
This will serve as an alibi, no?
Bukankah ini sebuah alibi?
True.
Kurasa begitu.
The victim was Mr. Shumoto?
Shumoto adalah korbannya?
What is your relationship with the victim?
Apa hubunganmu dengan korban?
"Naho Ojiro (26), Customer" -He was my ex-boyfriend.
"Naho Ojiro (26), Tamu Akuarium" -Dia mantan kekasihku.
It's already been a year since we split, though.
Sudah lebih dari setahun sejak kami putus.
Then, why did you ignore his call?
Kenapa kau mengabaikan teleponnya?
Because he kept bugging me to reconcile time and again so...
Dia terus berusaha untuk kembali bersama.
I was dating today too.
Aku sedang berkencan hari ini.
That's why I had my cell phone switched off.
Jadi aku mematikan ponselku.
Then...
Lalu...
you were with your date right through?
Apa kau bersama kekasihmu sepanjang waktu?
Yes.
Ya.
This is him.
Ini dia.
You can ask him if you need to.
Kau bisa tanya dia.
But, testimonies of lovers don't...
Tapi pernyataan seorang kekasih...
Come to think of it.
Dipikir-pikir tentangnya.
Just about the time the incident occurred,
Ketika itu terjadi,
I was taking a movie.
aku sedang merekam.
Really?
Benarkah?
It's been about 10 minutes already
Sudah sepuluh menit
but nothing's happening.
tapi tidak ada yang terjadi.
It's after this...
Selepas ini...
Ran, go back to the entrance and get the staff for me!
Ran, pergilah ke pintu masuk dan panggilkan seorang pegawai!
-We're in the movie. -Quick!
-Kita ada di dalam rekaman. -Cepat!
-No joke. -Shinichi.
-Sungguh? -Shinichi.
What was that?
Apa itu tadi?
This is his voice.
Itu suara kekasihku.
Something seems to have happened.
Sesuatu terjadi.
Do you want to go look?
Haruskah kita memeriksanya?
No, no. I don't want to get involved.
Tidak, tidak. Mari kita jangan terlibat.
This indeed seems to be a movie that you took.
Kau jelas tampaknya merekam video ini.
And why was Mr. Shumoto here?
Kenapa Shumoto ada di sini?
It seems he was on a date with his girlfriend.
Dia sedang kencan dengan kekasihnya.
Then, maybe he just called
Mungkin dia menelepon
because he wanted to introduce her to me.
agar dia bisa mengenalkannya padaku.
"Beika Aquarium"
"Akuarium Beika"
You must be the one going with Ms. Naho Ojiro?
Apa kau mengencani Naho Ojiro?
Yes. How do you know?
Ya. Bagaimana kau tahu itu?
She just told me a while ago.
Dia memberitahu kami.
She also told me that the one who was killed here today
Dan pria yang terbunuh di sini hari ini
used to be her ex-boyfriend.
adalah mantan kekasihnya.
What?
Apa?
"Kohdai Jinbei (28), Customer" -Naho's ex-boyfriend was killed?
"Kohdai Jinbe (28), Tamu Akuarium" -Mantan kekasih Naho dibunuh?
Really?
Benarkah?
You know him too, don't you?
Kau kenal dia, bukan?
No way. It's a first.
Tentu tidak. Itu berita untukku.
But, your mail address was also in his cell phone
Tapi, alamat surelmu ada di ponselnya
and you ignored the text mail that I sent you a while ago too, didn't you?
dan kau mengabaikan surel yang aku kirimkan kepada kau tadi.
Yeah, you mean the mail that said,
Maksudmu yang mengatakan,
"Contact me right away?"
"Segera hubungi aku?"
Since it was the same as the crank mail that I got before,
Aku menerima pesan iseng dari alamat itu sebelumnya,
I deleted it.
jadi aku langsung menghapusnya.
I get a lot of those recently.
Aku banyak mendapatkannya belakangan ini.
"If you want to hear my secret, click here."
"Klik untuk melihat rahasiaku."
It were sexually provoking mails.
Hal-hal mencurigakan seperti itu.
Was the sender Naho's ex-boyfriend?
Maksudmu itu berasal dari mantan kekasih Naho?
Yes.
Ya.
By the way, at the time of the crime,
Kau tampaknya sedang merekam dengannya
it seems you were also taking movies like she was.
ketika insiden itu terjadi.
Yeah.
Oh, benar.
Maybe...
Maksudmu...
You mean this?
Video ini?
Ran, go back to the entrance and get the staff for me!
Ran, pergilah ke pintu masuk dan panggilkan seorang pegawai!
Quick!
Cepat!
What was that?
Apa itu tadi?
Something seems to have happened.
Sesuatu terjadi.
Do you want to go look?
Haruskah kita memeriksanya?
No, no. I don't want to get involved.
Tidak, tidak. Mari kita jangan terlibat.
Right.
Kau benar.
Of course even before this, the movie was taken without interruption.
Ada 10 menit sebelum ini tanpa henti.
Because we were both planning to upload the movie on the blog later.
Kami akan mengunggahnya di blog kami nanti.
Inspector Megure.
Inspektur Megure.
There were other viewers who filmed the dolphin show,
Kami sudah bandingkan video pertunjukkan lumba-lumba
so we checked them against what Ms. Nakagiri took
milik Nakagiri dengan tamu lainnya.
and found there were no discrepancies.
Itu jelas diambil ketika insiden itu terjadi.
I see.
Begitu.
Why of all places did the perpetrator choose that tunnel
Tapi kenapa pelaku memilih terowongan itu
as a place to commit the crime?
untuk melakukan jenayahnya?
If it were the corridor where the normal fish tanks are lined out,
Sebagian besar lorong tangki ikan
it's dark so the other people
terlalu gelap
can only make out the silhouette of the perpetrator.
untuk melihat lebih dari siluet.
Why did the perpetrator deliberately choose such a bright tunnel?
Kenapa mereka memilih terowongan yang terang itu?
Ran, lend me your cell phone.
Ran, biar kupinjam ponselmu.
I forgot to bring mine.
Aku lupa membawa punyaku.
Okay.
Baik.
Don't break it.
Tapi jangan merusaknya.
Because I finally got Dad to buy it for me.
Ayahku akhirnya membelikanku yang ini.
Sorry, but will you please look the other way?
Bisakah kau berbalik?
Hey, what's with you? What?
Tunggu, apa? Apa?
Just what are you up to?
Apa yang sedang kau lakukan?
What do you mean what?
Apa maksud kau?
I'm wondering if that tunnel holds any meaning...
Aku pikir terowongan itu mungkin memiliki perbedaan...
Well, of course.
Tentunya.
Because no matter where you look
Itu karena ada ikan
there's nothing more but all kinds of fishes,
di manapun kau melihat
and it's as if you're at the bottom of sea!
rasanya seperti kau berada di dasar laut!
Like I said...
Itu sebabnya...
It's romantic like a dating spot...
itu adalah sebuah tempat romantis untuk berkencan...
Shinichi?
Shinichi?
I see.
Itu dia.
That's why the perpetrator chose that place.
Itu sebabnya pelaku memilihnya.
He chose this place because he wanted to replicate the ocean,
Tempat ini yang tampaknya dikelilingi oleh lautan,
and this place is exactly that!
maka itulah tempatnya!
Hey, just what do you mean?
Apa yang sedang terjadi?
All the others have gone home,
Semua orang sudah pergi.
and yet why are we the only ones here?
Kenapa kami harus tetap tinggal?
I showed it to you, didn't I?
Aku sudah menunjukkan videoku, bukan?
The movie to prove my alibi.
Video sebagai bukti alibiku.
You saw mine too, didn't you?
Kau juga sudah melihat punyaku, bukan?
Mine too.
Punyaku juga.
Yes, we did see it.
Ya, kami sudah melihatnya.
There's just one person that took a queer movie.
Tapi salah satunya aneh.
A movie that practically confesses
Itu pada dasarnya memberitahu kami
that the person is a murderer.
bahawa kau telah melakukannya.
I hope you're not going to say that it's the dolphin show that I took?
Jangan bilang itu adalah video pertunjukkan lumba-lumbaku.
The movie you took was terrible.
Videomu buruk.
The images were blurred
Itu bergetar
and the voices were cracked,
dan kualitas suaranya buruk.
that it wasn't worth watching.
Tak seorangpun bisa menonton itu.
I couldn't help it. Because I...
Aku tak bisa apa-apa. Lagipula, aku...
Right.
Itu benar.
It's only natural
Itu wajar
because you're an amateur.
karena kau seorang amatir.
On the contrary,
Dibandingkan milikmu,
the movie that Mr. Jinbe took was fantastic!
video Jinbe fantastis!
He had taken a great shot of the shark
Kau mendapat gambaran jelas ikan hiu
that was swimming gracefully.
yang sedang berenang.
Am I going to end up being the perpetrator because of it?
Dan itu menjadikanku pembunuhnya?
No, you're probably just used to taking movies.
Tidak. Kau hanya terbiasa mengambil video.
You wanted to upload the movie onto your blog too.
Kau juga akan mengunggahnya di blogmu.
The movie in question is...
Masalahnya adalah...
the one that your girlfriend,
milik kekasihmu.
Naho Ojiro took!
Video milik Naho Ojiro!
This is that movie.
Ini adalah video-videonya.
This was taken by Mr. Jinbe
Ini milik Jinbe
and the one on this side was taken by Ms. Ojiro.
dan ini milik Ojiro.
Don't you notice anything?
Menyadari sesuatu?
What do you mean?
Apa maksud kau?
Mine is taken sideways
Punyaku horizontal
and hers is taken vertically.
dan punya dia vertikal.
Yes. Normally, if you want to film a fish that is long sideways,
Biasanya jika kau ingin merekam seekor ikan yang panjang,
you would take it sideways, like Mr. Jimbei, wouldn't you?
kau akan merekam secara horizontal seperti Jinbe, bukan?
In order to get the entire body into the frame.
Kau menginginkan seluruh tubuhnya terekam.
However, Ms. Ojiro took the movie vertically.
Tapi video milik Ojiro vertikal.
Just as expected, the shark that was in her movie,
Ikan hiu itu melewati bingkai
framed out in no time at all.
dan menghilang dengan cepat.
I wasn't interested in taking the shark.
Aku tidak berusaha untuk merekam ikan hiu itu.
That's not the only thing that's strange.
Bukan itu saja yang aneh.
When somebody is taking pictures of something,
Biasanya orang menghindari berjalan ke dalam rekaman
it's common sense to try to avoid interrupting the cameraman.
ketika mereka melihat seseorang sedang merekam.
Like in this movie taken by Mr. Jinbe
Seperti yang kau lihat dalam video milik Jinbe.
But, in Ms. Ojiro's movie,
Tapi tidak ada yang melakukan itu
nobody seems to give a care,
dalam video milik Ojiro.
and they are interrupting left and right.
Mereka berjalan melalui rekaman itu.
It's almost as if they're not aware
Seolah mereka tidak tahu
that she's even taking a picture.
dia sedang merekam.
That's because...
Aku...
It's only natural that they're not aware
Tidak heran mereka tidak menyadarinya
because she had her cell phone...
karena dia meletakkan ponselnya...
inside his knitted cap, here,
di dalam topinya, di sini,
while taking the movie!
dan merekam videonya!
Even if a white cell phone were to be stuck into a white knitted cap,
Kau harus melihat dengan teliti
unless you take a good look, it's quite inconspicuous.
untuk menyadari sebuah ponsel putih dalam topi putih.
Placed this way, she gets to take movies as if she were behind him.
Video ini tampak seperti dia mengambilnya dari belakang dia.
That's why she chose the tunnel of this fish tank!
Itu sebabnya dia memilih terowongan ini.
The front and back are full of fish,
Dengan ikan di segala sisi,
no matter what the shot,
ikan akan muncul dalam rekaman
there is some kind of fish in the frame of the camera.
bagaimanapun caramu merekamnya.
But, if he had something like that in his cap,
Tapi bukankah dia akan menyadari
you'd think he'd notice, right?
jika dia meletakkannya di dalam topinya?
She probably said there's something on your cap
Dia mungkin mengatakan ada sesuatu di topinya,
and made him take it off once,
melepaskannya,
buried the cell phone into the knitted cap,
memasukkan ponselnya,
then put it back on him again.
dan memasangnya kembali.
You can remove the cell phone in the wink of an eye.
Hanya butuh satu detik untuk mengeluarkan ponsel itu.
There was a part in her movie that was blurred, wasn't there?
Videonya menjadi buram pada satu titik.
That's when she removed it.
Itu ketika dia mengeluarkannya.
But people tend to move their faces unconsciously,
Tapi orang secara tidak sadar menggerakkan kepala mereka.
so I wonder if it's possible for someone to take something so fixed.
Videonya seharusnya tidak begitu stabil.
That can be explained.
Jangan cemaskan itu.
Because he...
Lagipula, kekasihnya...
He hurt his neck and head neck braces on,
Dia sedang mengenakan penyangga untuk lehernya yang cedera.
so his head was more or less set in place.
Dia tak bisa tiba-tiba menggerakkan kepalanya.
How do you know about my braces?
Bagaimana kau tahu?
When I called out to you from the side,
Ketika aku bicara dari sampingmu,
you turned your body and all towards me.
kau memutar seluruh tubuhmu daripada hanya lehermu.
And even when watching the movie,
Selagi melihat videomu,
you brought the cell phone right up in front of your face.
kau memegang ponselmu tepat di depan wajahmu.
That's why I thought that you hurt your neck
Begitulah cara aku tahu dia tak bisa menunduk
and couldn't look down.
karena lehernya yang cedera.
Which means that while she was letting him take the movie,
Lalu selagi dia merekam,
Ms. Ojiro went to commit the crime.
Ojiro membunuh dia.
Yes. She had it set to see the victim at this tunnel,
Ya. Dia menemukan korban menunggunya di dalam terowongan ini
and after rendering him unconscious with a stun gun,
dan menggunakan sebuah pistol setrum untuk membuatnya pingsan.
she went on to pierce his heart with a knife and stab him to death.
Lalu dia menikam jantungnya.
Then, she went back to Mr. Jinbe
Dia kembali pada kekasihnya
to retrieve the cell phone.
dan mengambil kembali ponselnya.
But, it's a miracle nobody saw her.
Aku terkejut tak seorang pun melihat dia.
She was probably dressed so that it wouldn't hurt being witnessed.
Tidak masalah jika ada yang melihat dia.
If she removes her jacket and lifts her skirt up,
Jika dia melepaskan mantelnya, mengangkat roknya,
then wear a cap or something,
dan mengenakan topi,
she'd look like a different person.
dia tampak seperti orang berbeda.
Once she gets out of the bright tunnel,
Di luar terowongan yang terang itu
that rest is practically all dark.
adalah amat gelap.
This way, changing clothes wouldn't be a problem.
Cukup mudah untuk berubah.
But however, it's too bad...
Sayangnya,
there was just one thing you couldn't change.
ada satu hal yang tak bisa kau ubah.
Yes. It's this glove.
Ya, sarung tangan ini.
It's reversible
Karena mereka bisa dibalik,
so it seems that you're wearing it inside out to hide the fact...
kau membaliknya untuk menyembunyikannya...
See, just as I thought,
Aku tahu itu.
the blood of the victim is on the fingertips of your right hand.
Darah korban ada pada jari kananmu.
How'd you know?
Bagaimana kau tahu?
The picture you took with him that you showed me.
Foto yang kau ambil dengan kekasihmu.
Judging from what you're wearing, I know you took it today.
Berdasarkan pakaianmu, aku tahu kau mengambilnya hari ini.
But, the color of your gloves were different.
Tapi warna sarung tanganmu berbeda.
People normally don't bring two different gloves with them.
Tidak ada yang bepergian dengan dua pasang sarung tangan.
Besides, that picture is what you took using your right hand.
Dan kau mengambilnya dengan tangan kananmu.
You handed the Inspector your cell phone with your right hand.
Kau juga menunjukkan ponselmu pada inspektur dengan tangan kananmu.
You are apparently right-handed
Kau jelas bertangan kanan.
But, after taking off your glove,
Tapi kau melepas sarung tangan kirimu
you worked your cell phone with your left hand.
dan menggunakan ponselmu dengan tangan kirimu.
Putting all these together,
Fakta-fakta ini,
with the fact that a bit of blood
dan fakta bahwa ada darah yang tumpah
was on the inside of the bag of the convenience store,
melalui kantong plastik
that the perpetrator used to stab the victim.
yang digunakan pelaku untuk menikam korban,
Simple summing up leads me to my conclusion.
menuju pada kesimpulan ini.
Let's have forensics check the blood then.
Kami akan minta forensik memeriksa.
If you're going to check, I'd like you to do it fast.
Cepat dan periksalah.
I'm dying to wash the blood of that guy off of me
Aku ingin mencuci darah pria itu
as soon as I possibly can you see.
secepat mungkin.
So, you killed him after all, Naho?
Maka, Naho, apa itu artinya kau membunuhnya?
Yes, I did.
Ya, itu benar.
He threatened to distribute indecent pictures of me
Dia mengancam untuk menyebarkan foto-foto memalukan
over the net because I dumped him.
secara daring karena putus dengannya.
That guy said that he sent several to your cell phone too.
Dia bilang dia sudah mengirimkan beberapa padamu.
So, that's where that indecent text mail came from...
Jadi surel-surel itu...
Right.
Itu benar.
If you opened it you would've found an indecent picture of me.
Di dalamnya adalah foto-fotoku yang memalukan yang dia ambil.
It seems though, that you deleted it without opening it.
Walau kau menghapusnya tanpa membukanya.
How'd he get my mail address?
Bagaimana dia mendapatkan alamatku?
When I went over to his house to tell him that I wanted to split.
Ketika aku pergi ke rumahnya untuk putus,
That guy when I went to the restroom,
dia menggunakan ponselku
seems to have looked through my cell phone.
selagi aku berada di kamar kecil.
He told me, "If you don't want me sending your indecent pictures
"Jika kau tak ingin kekasih, karyawan di tempat kerja,
to your boyfriend, work place and family, pay me.
dan keluargamu melihat foto-foto ini, berikan aku uang."
I'm up to my neck with debt."
"Aku banyak berhutang."
That's why I decided to distribute his blood instead.
Jadi aku menumpahkan darahnya saja.
But, I goofed.
Tapi aku gagal.
If I didn't turn my glove inside out because I got blood on it,
Jika aku tidak membalik sarung tanganku,
I may have been able to get away with it.
kau mungkin tidak tahu.
No.
Tidak.
It was obvious even if you didn't turn your gloves inside out.
Itu jelas tanpa mereka.
In the movie that Mr. Jinbe took,
Dalam video Jinbe,
you wore gloves on both hands.
kau mengenakan kedua sarung tanganmu.
You used your left hand to work the cell phone
Kau melepaskan satu ketika kau menggunakan tangan kirimu,
and back then your gloves were the knitted kind.
jadi mereka adalah sarung tangan wool biasa.
It's hard to work a smart phone unless your hands are bare
Kau perlu tanganmu untuk menggunakan sebuah ponsel pintar.
That just goes to show and serves as proof
Itu adalah bukti
that you needed gloves to do what you were trying to carry out.
kau melakukan sesuatu yang membutuhkan kau untuk mengenakannya.
It's a simple deduction.
Itu adalah sebuah asumsi sederhana.
I think that it's better to call the whole thing
Kau harus menyudahinya.
about the lovey-dovey re-encounter project off,
Setelah apa yang terjadi,
because of this incident that happened here at this aquarium.
kau seharusnya tidak menggunakan Rencana Reuni Romantismu di sana.
I guess so.
Kau benar.
Oh, no. It's raining.
Hujan!
Let's run home then.
Mari kita lari pulang.
Hey, I told you not to run.
Hei, aku sudah menyuruhmu untuk tidak lari.
But, why?
Kenapa tidak?
My cell phone!
Ponselku!
No.
Tidak mungkin.
Why was my cell phone in my hood?
Kenapa ada di dalam tudungku?
Sorry.
Maaf.
I was thinking of where the perpetrator put the cell phone
Aku berpikir di mana pelaku meletakkan ponselnya
to take the movie
untuk merekam.
and forgot that I hid it in your hood.
Aku lupa aku meletakkannya di dalam tudungmu.
So, what are you going to do about it?
Bagaimana bisa kau melakukan ini?
Dad just bought it for me.
Aku baru mendapatkannya.
Don't cry.
Jangan menangis.
I'll buy you a new one someday.
Aku akan belikan yang baru.
You're the pits. Really!
Ini payah!
Nothing good happens when I'm with you!
Tak ada hal baik yang pernah terjadi ketika aku bersamamu!
Even when I went to the States,
Ketika kita pergi ke Amerika,
all I did was run into crimes.
masalah juga terus terjadi.
Okay, then...
Baiklah.
Tropical Land! I'll take you there!
Tanah Tropis! Aku akan membawamu ke sana!
Tropical Land?
Tanah Tropis?
What's with that happy sounding place?
Itu sebuah tempat yang ceria.
I hear they're going to be making it in Tokyo.
Mereka mendirikannya di Tokyo.
I'm sure that no crimes can happen at an amusement park.
Aku yakin tidak ada yang akan terjadi di sebuah taman bermain.
I don't mind going if you're treating me to everything.
Aku akan pergi jika kau membayar semuanya.
Why don't we go and you treat me
Baik, lalu bagaimana kalau kita pergi dan kau mentraktir aku
if I win the Tokyo Karate Championship?
jika aku memenangkan turnamen karateku?
Hey, hold it.
Hei, tunggu.
You were the runner up last year
Tahun lalu kau juara dua.
and didn't the Senior upper classman that won the championship
Peserta tahun ketiga yang memenangkan
quit the club already?
berhenti dari tim, bukan?
You promised, okay!
Itu sebuah janji!
I don't get much of an allowance.
Aku tidak punya banyak uang saku.
And if you're getting me a cell phone,
Dan jika kau membelikanku sebuah ponsel,
make sure you get me the sea cucumber man
belikan juga tali timun laut
that they sell at the Beika Aquarium too.
dari akuarium.
Yes, ma'am.
Baik, baik.
I was half joking
Aku bercanda.
and yet he really went out and bought it for me.
Aku tak bisa percaya dia benar-benar membelikannya.
But, I wonder how he really felt about me back then.
Aku juga penasaran tentang perasaan Shinichi kepadaku ketika itu.
I wonder if he...
Apa Shinichi sudah...
Oh, no.
Oh, tidak.
"Heart pounding" -I'm getting this unstoppable urge to want to ask him.
"Jantung berdebar kencang" -Sekarang aku sangat ingin bertanya.
Shinichi's cell phone?
Ponsel milik Shinichi?
"Incoming call, Ran Mouri"
"Panggilan masuk, Mori Ran"
From Ran?
Itu dari Ran?
Shinichi?
Shinichi?
Ran.
Ran.
Where do you think I am now?
Tebak di mana aku.
I'm at the Beika Aquarium where I came with you before.
Aku di Akuarium Beika yang kita kunjungi bersama.
Yeah. That place where the stabbing took place.
Tempat di mana pria itu ditikam, ya?
By the way,
Bagaimanapun,
I have something I want to ask you about.
aku ingin menanyakan sesuatu padamu.
Back then, did you... you know, Shinichi..
Saat itu, apa kau...
What did you think of...
Apa perasaanmu...
Oh, you mean that?
Apa maksudmu?
When I told you not to run, right?
Bagaimana aku menyuruhmu untuk tidak berlari, bukan?
That's not it?
Bukan?
Oh, yes. Well, that too but...
Oh, ya. Kurasa ada itu juga...
Right, that was sort of bugging me too.
Dipikir-pikir, aku juga penasaran tentang itu.
Back the you said
Waktu itu, ternyata
that all you were doing was checking the mail from your mother
kau hanya memeriksa pesan ibumu
and didn't respond to Sonoko's mail, right?
dan tidak merespon pesan Sonoko, bukan?
Moreover, you were using your left-hand then.
Kau menggunakan tangan kirimu.
You probably hurt your right hand,
Kau mungkin melukai tangan kananmu
so you couldn't do something complex as to respond to a mail.
dan tidak cukup tangkas untuk menulis sebuah surel.
Since you didn't take off your glove,
Karena kau tidak melepas sarung tanganmu,
you must've had a bandage on your hand.
kau mungkin memperban tanganmu.
But, since you were all excited saying
Kau bersikeras
that you were going to win the championship,
untuk memenangkan turnamenmu,
you probably just sprained your finger or something.
jadi kupikir itu hanya jari yang terkilir.
Right, I got hurt during karate practice.
Ya, benar. Itu terjadi selama latihan.
But, what does that have to do with telling me not to run?
Tapi bagaimana itu mencegahku dari berlari?
It's because with a finger like that you could never...
Karena kau tak bisa menyambungkannya dengan jarimu.
hook on your bra.
Kaitan pada bramu.
After all, you only have the kind that have hooks in the back.
Kau hanya memiliki yang kaitannya di belakang.
How do you know something like that?
Bagaimana kau tahu itu?
My seat was right behind yours,
Aku duduk di belakangmu,
so each time you bent forward,
jadi aku bisa melihat
I couldn't help but see it.
ketika kau membungkuk ke depan.
I can't picture you asking that goofy detective,
Kau takkan pernah membiarkan
Dad of yours to hook it on.
ayahmu mengaitkan bramu untukmu.
Sonoko had a cold.
Sonoko terkena flu.
And it's hard to believe you would go all the way to your Mom
Dan kau takkan pergi menemui ibumu
just to ask her to do it for you.
hanya untuk memakai bra.
In other words, you weren't wearing a bra back then...
Dengan kata lain, kau tidak mengenakan bra...
You may not know it,
Kau mungkin tidak tahu,
but if you run without a bra, your boobs will sway to no end
tapi ketika kau berlari tanpa sebuah bra, payudaramu memantul,
and the Cooper's ligaments that support your breasts will stretch
membuat ligamen Coopermu meregang
causing your breast to start sagging.
dan merosot seiring waktu.
Idiot!
Kau bodoh!
I use them, the ones called sports bras!
Aku mengenakan bra olahraga!
Oh, right!
Oh, benar!
I forgot that she used them at the school club activity.
Aku lupa dia menggunakannya untuk latihan.
And when it comes to the bras with hooks behind,
Di samping itu, bahkan dengan bra kaitan belakang,
all I have to do is hook it up after bringing it in front like this
kau bisa memasangnya di depan
and spin it around like this.
dan memutarnya ke belakang.
Just what do you think you're making me say, stupid!
Kenapa kau membuatku mengatakan itu? Dasar bodoh!
I hung up.
Aku akan menutup.
So, what did she call me for anyway?
Kenapa sebenarnya dia menelepon?
"Next Episode"
"Episode Selanjutnya"
This is "Anxiety."
Ini adalah "Kegelisahan."
What is the meaning of this?
Apa maksudmu?
The car that was in front of us with the "Scream" in it,
Mobil di depan yang membawa "Teriakan"
suddenly went off route and disappeared!
tiba-tiba keluar jalur dan menghilang.
It's like a three-panel cartoon.
Itu seperti komik tiga panel.
It's about the "Scream" drawn by Munch being stolen, right?
"Teriakan" Munch dicuri, bukan?
How do you know?
Bagaimana kau tahu?
This was a crime!
Ini bukanlah kecelakaan!
Next Conan,
Selanjutnya dalam Conan,
"Munch's Scream Disappears"
"Menghilangnya Teriakan Munch"